Guide to the David Cassel papers, 1950-2009.
Cassel, David papers
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
David Cassel papers, 1949-2006.
14-22-3899
Cassel, David G.
5.5 cubic feet.
Correspondence, publications
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Professional papers and correspondence.
ORGANIZATIONAL HISTORY
Cornell University professor of physics.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Professional papers and correspondence relating to his work at Newman Laboratory and in the Physics Department, especially files relating to the Cornell Electron Storage Ring (CESR) and the Superconducting Supercollider (SSC).
SUBJECTS
Names:
Cassel, David G.; Cornell University--Faculty.; Cornell University.Dept. of Physics.
Subjects:
Physics--New York (State)--History; Particle acceleration; Superconducting Super Collider; Nuclear physics.; Electrons--Capture
INFORMATION FOR USERS
CONTAINER LIST
- Laboratory of Nuclear Studies (LNS) History, 1949-1980 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Cornell Electron Storage Ring (CESR) Upgrade Plans, 1992-1995 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Cornell Electron Storage Ring (CESR) as a B Factory, 1987-1991 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- B Factories - General Articles, 1990-1994 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- B Factory Workshop, September 1990 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Joint Review for B Factory Proposal - Organization, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Joint Review - Accelerator Issues, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Joint Review - Detector Issues, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Joint Review - Critique of PEP-II and BaBar, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Joint Review - Tracking Acceptance and Resolution, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Joint Review - CsI Cost and Performance, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Joint Review - Measuring Xs, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Joint Review - Report, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Joint Review - Electric Power, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Joint Review - Cornell Infrastructure, 1991-1992 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Joint Review - Report Drafts, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 16)
- International CLEO Particle Detecror Collaborators, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 17)
- B Factory Decision, 1993-1994 (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Stanford Linear Accerlator Centre (SLAC) ABF Updates, 1991-1992 (Box 1, Folder 19)
- Townes Subpanel, September 1991 (Box 1, Folder 20)
- Townes Subpanel, November 1991 (Box 1, Folder 21)
- High Energy Physics Advisory Panel (HEPAP) Subpanel - Cornell, January 24, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 22)
- Cornell - National Science Foundation (NSF) and the B Factory, 1992-1993 (Box 1, Folder 23)
- Cornell Electron Storage Ring (CESR)-B - Updates, 1991-1992 (Box 1, Folder 24)
- CESR-B - NYS Initiatives, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 25)
- B Factory Workshop, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 26)
- High Energy Physics Advisory Panel (HEPAP), 1991-1992 (Box 1, Folder 27)
- Tigner Celebration, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 28)
- Lepton-Photon Conference Plans, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 29)
- CESR B Factory - I, 1989-1991 (Box 1, Folder 30)
- Cornell and Congress, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 31)
- CESR-B Cost Review, July 1991 (Box 1, Folder 32)
- CESR-B Technical Review, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 33)
- High Energy Physics Advisory Panel (HEPAP) - Transparencies, 1988-1989 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- VAX/8600 Computers, 1989 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Universities Research Association (URA) Bulletins, 1992 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- URA Lattice, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- URA Bulletins, 1991 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Users Organization for the Superconducting Super Collider (UOSSC) - Newsletters, 1989-1992 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Superconducting Super Collider (SSC) Newsletters, 1989-1994 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- SSC News, 1990-1991 (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Texas National Research Laboratory Commission (TNRLC), 1989 (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Drell Panel on SSC Energy, 1990 (Box 2, Folder 10)
- SSC Energy - Ad Hoc Committee, 1989 (Box 2, Folder 11)
- SSC and Congress, 1993 (Box 2, Folder 12)
- SSC Congressional Activity, 1992 (Box 2, Folder 13)
- SSC Congressional Activity, 1990 (Box 2, Folder 14)
- SSC Congressional Activity, 1989 (Box 2, Folder 15)
- SSC - General Articles, 1988-1994 (Box 2, Folder 16)
- SSC Conference, October 1989 (Box 2, Folder 17)
- SSC Budget and Spending Profile, 1991 (Box 2, Folder 18)
- SSC Policy and Schedules, 1989-1991 (Box 2, Folder 19)
- SSC - EMPACT Detector, 1989 (Box 2, Folder 20)
- SSC - BCD Detector, 1989-1990 (Box 2, Folder 21)
- SSC - Forward B Detector, 1989 (Box 2, Folder 22)
- SSC Soleniod Detectors, 1989 (Box 2, Folder 23)
- SSC Experiments, 1985 (Box 2, Folder 24)
- UOSSC, October - December 1989 (Box 2, Folder 25)
- UOSSC, January - March 1990 (Box 2, Folder 26)
- UOSSC, July - Septermber 1989 (Box 2, Folder 27)
- UOSSC, January - March 1989 (Box 2, Folder 28)
- UOSSC, April - June 1989 (Box 2, Folder 29)
- UOSSC, July - September 1988 (Box 2, Folder 30)
- UOSSC, October - December 1988 (Box 2, Folder 31)
- SSC Telephone Directory, 1990 (Box 2, Folder 32)
- URA Bulletins, 1990 (Box 2, Folder 33)
- URA Bulletins, 1989 (Box 2, Folder 34)
- UOSSC Correspondence, 1990 (Box 2, Folder 35)
- UOSSC Correspondence, 1989 (Box 2, Folder 36)
- UOSSC, July - September 1991 (Box 2, Folder 37)
- UOSSC, April - June 1991 (Box 2, Folder 38)
- UOSSC, July - September 1990 (Box 2, Folder 39)
- UOSSC, April - June 1990 (Box 2, Folder 40)
- UOSSC, October - December 1990 (Box 2, Folder 41)
- UOSSC, January - March 1991 (Box 2, Folder 42)
- UOSSC Finances, 1988-1989 (Box 2, Folder 43)
- American Physical Society (APS) Divison of Particles and Fields (DPF) - Newsletters, 1989-1996 (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Handouts - DPF Meeting, 1996 (Box 3, Folder 2)
- DPF Conference, 1995 (Box 3, Folder 3)
- DPF Newsletters, 1989-1993 (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Congressional Reception, 1995 (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Physical Review D (PRD) Page Charges, 1995 (Box 3, Folder 6)
- DPF, 1995 (Box 3, Folder 7)
- DPF Meeting, 1994 (Box 3, Folder 8)
- American Physical Society (APS), 1995-1996 (Box 3, Folder 9)
- DPF, 1992-1993 (Box 3, Folder 10)
- DPF Meeting, 1996 (Box 3, Folder 11)
- APS April Meeting, 1996 (Box 3, Folder 12)
- Physics 360, 1972 (Box 3, Folder 13)
- Quarterly Report, 1999-2003 (Box 3, Folder 14)
- Lab for Elementary-Particle Physics (LEPP) Reports, 2002 (Box 3, Folder 15)
- Laboratory for Nuclear Studies (LNS) Reports, 2001 (Box 3, Folder 16)
- LNS Reports, 2000 (Box 3, Folder 17)
- LNS Reports, 1999 (Box 3, Folder 18)
- LNS Reports, 1998 (Box 3, Folder 19)
- LNS Reports, 1997 (Box 3, Folder 20)
- LNS Reports, 1996 (Box 3, Folder 21)
- LNS Reports, 1995 (Box 3, Folder 22)
- LNS Reports, 1994 (Box 3, Folder 23)
- LNS Reports, 1993 (Box 3, Folder 24)
- LNS Reports, 1992 (Box 3, Folder 25)
- LNS Reports, 1991 (Box 3, Folder 26)
- LNS Reports, 1990 (Box 3, Folder 27)
- LNS Reports, 1989 (Box 3, Folder 28)
- LNS Reports, 1988 (Box 3, Folder 29)
- LNS Reports, 1987 (Box 4, Folder 1)
- LNS Reports, 1986 (Box 4, Folder 2)
- LNS Reports, 1985 (Box 4, Folder 3)
- LNS Reports, 1984 (Box 4, Folder 4)
- LNS Spending - Monthly, 1984 (Box 4, Folder 5)
- Cornell High Energy Synchotron Source (CHESS) Policy Board and Users, 1992 (Box 4, Folder 6)
- CESR Program Advisory Committee (PAC) Meeting, 1993 (Box 4, Folder 7)
- CESR PAC Meeting, 1992 (Box 4, Folder 8)
- CESR PAC Report, 1991 (Box 4, Folder 9)
- CESR PAC Report, 1990 (Box 4, Folder 10)
- CLEO PAC Report, 1989 (Box 4, Folder 11)
- CESR PAC Report, 1988 (Box 4, Folder 12)
- PAC Meetings, 1985 (Box 4, Folder 13)
- PAC Meetings, 1984 (Box 4, Folder 14)
- Design Report for CESR, April 1977 (Box 4)
- The 10 to 20 GEV Cornell Electron Synchotron, May 1967 (Box 4)
- CESR - Proposal to the National Science Foundation (NSF) for Operational Support, November 1987-October 1990 (Box 4)
- Design Study Proposal: A High Energy, High Luminosity Electron Positron Collider Based on Superconducting RF Cavities, May 1980 (Box 4)
- Progress Report on a Design and Development Study for CESR II: A High Energy, High Luminosity Electron Positron Collider Based on Superconducting RF Cavities, May 1981 (Box 4)
- Design Report - CESR, October 1976 (Box 4)
- CESR: An Electron-Positron Colliding Beam Facility - A Proposal to the NSF, October 1977 (Box 4)
- Cornell Electron Synchotron - A Proposal to the NSF for Operational Support, February 1977-January 1978 (Box 4)
- CESR - A Proposal to the NSF for Operational Support, November 1979-October 1982 (Box 4)
- CLEO - Report to the Program Advisory Committee (PAC), December 1986 (Box 4)
- CESR Design Report, April 1977 (Box 4)
- Working Towards Establishin a B-Factory - Conference at Syracuse University Proceedings, September 1989 (Box 4)
- CLEO II - A Proposal for an Upgrade of the CLEO Detector for the Study of e+ e- Interactions at CESR, May 1984 (Box 4)
- CLEO II - Updated Proposal for an Upgrade of the CLEO Detector for the Study of e+ e- Interactions at CESR, January 1985 (Box 4)
- What Can We Hope to Learn from B Meson Decay? - Proceedings of CLEO Collaboration Workshop, July 1981 (Box 4)
- CESR - A Proposal to the NSF for Operational Support, November 1989-October 1990 (Box 4)
- Prospects for a CESR B-Factory Upgrade - by Members of the CESR/CLEO Staff, 1989 (Box 4)
- CESR - A Proposal to the NSF for Operational Support, November 1984-October 1987 (Box 5)
- Report of the PAC - LNS, February 9, 1988 (Box 5)
- CESR - A Proposal to the NSF for Operational Support, November 1988-October 1989 (Box 5)
- CESR - A Proposal to the NSF for Operational Support, November 1986-October 1987 (Box 5)
- CESR - A Proposal to the NSF for Operational Support, November 1985-October 1986 (Box 5)
- Cornell Electron Synchotron - A Proposal to the NSF for Operational Support, March 1976-February 1977 (Box 5)
- Electron-Positron Colliding Beam Facility at Cornell - A Proposal to the NSF for Construction Funds, May 1975 (Box 5)
- CESR B-Factory Upgrade - Presentation to HEPAP Subpanel, February 8, 1990 (Box 5)
- CESR B-Factory - Updated Proposal for B-Factory Upgrade for the CESR, June 1993 (Box 5)
- CESR-B - Conceptual Design for a B-Factory Based On CESR, June 1993 (Box 5)
- The CLEO III Detector - Status Report, December 1996 (Box 5)
- The CLEO III Detector Upgrade Project - The CLEO Collaboration, February 1994 (Box 5)
- The CLEO III Detector - Design and Physics Goals, February 1994 (Box 5)
- CESR-B R and D Report, June 1993 (Box 5)
- CESR B-Factory - Detector for a B-Factory, June 1993 (Box 5)
- CESR B-Factory - Physics Rationale for a B-Factory, June 1993 (Box 5)
- Institute for the Teacing of Modern Physics and Technology: Development of Leadership Teams of teachers and Scientists - The B-Factory/CLEO Collaboration, January 1991 (Box 5)
- CESR-B - Conceptual Design for a B-Factory Based on CESR, 1991 (Box 5)
- CESR B-Factory - Detector for a B-Factory, February 1991 (Box 5)
- CESR B-Factory - Physics Rationale for a B-Factory, January 1991 (Box 5)
- CESR - A Proprosal to the NSF for Operational Support, November 1990-October 1993 (Box 5)
- CESR - A Proposal to the NSF for Operational Support, November 1991-October 1993 (Box 5)
- CESR - A Proposal to the NSF for Operational Support, November 1992-October 1993 (Box 5)
- CESR - A Proposal to the NSF for Operational Support, November 1993-October 1998 (Box 5)
- CESR B-Factory - Revised Proposal for a B-Factory Upgrade for the CESR, April 30, 1991 (Box 5)
- CESR B-Factory - Revised Proposal for a B-Factory Upgrade for the CESR, June 13, 1991 (Box 5)
- CESR B-Factory - Proposal for a B-Factory Upgrade for the CESR, February 1991 (Box 5)
- CESR - Annual Progress Report and Request for Continued Support, November 1994-October 1995; November 1995-October 1996 (Box 5)
- CESR - Annual Progress Report and Request for Continued Support, November 1995-October 1996; November 1996-October 1997 (Box 5)
- CESR - Annual Progress Report and Request for Continued Support, November 1996-October 1997; November 1997-October 1998 (Box 5)
- CESR - A Proposal to the NSF for Operational Support, November 1998-October 2003 (Box 5)
- Support of the CESR Facility - A Proposal to the NSF for Operational Support, November 2001-October 2006 (Box 5)
- CESR B Schedule and Cost (1), 1992 (Box 5, Folder 1)
- CESR B Schedule and Cost (2), 1991 (Box 5, Folder 2)
- PEP II - An Asymmetric B Factory Conceptual Design Report (1), June 1993 (Box 5, Folder 3)
- PEP II - An Asymmetric B Factory Conceptual Design Report (2), June 1993 (Box 5, Folder 4)
- PEP II B-Factory Joint Review - SLAC (1), June 1993 (Box 6, Folder 1)
- PEP II B-Factory Joint Review - SLAC (2), June 1993 (Box 6, Folder 2)
- PEP II B-Factory Joint Review - SLAC (3), June 1993 (Box 6, Folder 3)
- Joint B-Factory Review - CESR (1), June 1993 (Box 6, Folder 4)
- Joint B-Factory Review - CESR (2), June 1993 (Box 6, Folder 5)
- Joint B-Factory Review - CESR (3), June 1993 (Box 6, Folder 6)